We did it. Putting the work between us and that includes you,
我们做到了 我们和你一起协作
we managed to get our Wikipedia crawler up and running.
完成了我们的维基百科爬虫并使其运行
Let's review how we did it.
回顾一下我们是如何做到的
The very first thing we did was to try out clicking the wikipedia links by hand.
我们做的第一件事 尝试手动点击维基百科链接
We came to understand what we were trying to achieve with our program.
我们开始了解 想要程序实现的是什么
Next, we did some learning.
接下来 我们学习了一些东西
We found out about the structure of the input data HTML,
我们学习了输入数据 HTML 的结构
and we researched useful Python packages that would help us process it.
研究了有用的 Python 包 帮助我们处理 HTML
Next, we designed a program,
接下来 我们设计了一个程序
but without coding it up yet.
但没有编写代码
We made decisions about the kind of loop to use,
我们决定使用的循环种类
the data structures that we would need,
需要的数据结构
and decided the steps we would perform and their order.
并决定我们将要执行的步骤及其顺序
There was also a specific extra item that's important if you're interacting with the Web.
如果你正在与网络互动 还有一个特定的额外项很重要
We slowed the program down to avoid it being a nuisance.
我们放慢了程序 避免其成为滋扰
Only after all that work did we start writing code.
做完所有这些工作 我们才开始编写代码
Charlie wrote the continue_crawl function that controls the while loop,
Charlie 写了一个控制 while 循环的 continue_crawl 函数
and laid out the main steps inside of that while loop.
并布置了 while 循环中的主要步骤
In the process, she actually ended up planning a separate function, find_first_link.
在这个过程中 她最终规划了另一个函数 find_first_link
She worked out what it would need to do,
她规定了该函数需要做的事
but not actually how to do it.
但没有设定函数实际上的实现方式
I was the one who wrote the find_first_link function following Charlie's specification.
我是在 Charlie 的规范之后编写 find_first_link 函数的人
I also tested everything to make sure that code
同样 我也测试了代码 以确保其
worked on a variety of Wikipedia pages.
在各种维基百科页面上工作
I iterated on the code that I had written
我迭代了我写的代码
in order to make it work on every Wikipedia page that I found.
以使其在我发现的每个维基百科页面上工作
You can use these bullet points and
你可以使用这些要点以及
this example to help next time you're writing a program.
这个例子 可以对你下次编程有所帮助
Depending on the work you're doing,
根据你在做的具体工作
you might need to change the order,
你可能需要更改顺序
or repeat the step more than once.
或多次重复某些步骤
These are basic steps that you'll come back to again and again when you're programming.
这些是你在编程时需要一遍遍重复的基础步骤